What’s the first thing you remember doing?
你记忆中很早发生的事是什么？
It could be playing with your friends at school, or going to a birthday party and eating amazing cake.
可能是在学校和朋友们玩耍，或是去参加生日派对，吃到了美味的蛋糕。
Most of us have a treasured early memory of our childhood, but can we really believe those vivid memories?
我们大多数人都有一段珍藏的童年早期回忆，但那些鲜活的记忆真的可信吗？
Did those special moments really happen – or did we make them up?
那些特别的瞬间是真实发生过，还是我们自己编造出来的？
It’s a strange concept to grasp, but according to research, about four out of 10 of us invent our first childhood memory.
这是个让人难以理解的奇怪概念，但研究显示，大约十分之四的人会虚构自己的第一段童年记忆。
Rather than having experienced something, we could have fabricated a fake memory from videos or photos we’ve seen. We could have been influenced by a story recounted to us that spurs our minds on to adopt someone else’s memory as our own.
我们或许并没有亲身经历过某件事，而是通过看过的视频或照片编造出了一段虚假的记忆；也可能是受他人讲述的故事影响，从而将别人的记忆当成了自己的。
What it means is that memories of our younger years, especially before the age of two, may be inaccurate, or entirely false.
这意味着，我们儿时的记忆，尤其是两岁之前的记忆，可能是不准确的，甚至是完全虚假的。
But why don’t we have clear memories from that age?
但为什么我们没有那个年龄段的清晰记忆呢？
Well, our ability to retain memories from before the age of two isn’t great.
原因在于，我们保留两岁前记忆的能力并不强。
While at that age we do have short-term memories, according to Catherine Loveday, an expert in autobiographical memory at the University of Westminster, the memories that infants make are not long-lasting.
威斯敏斯特大学自传体记忆专家凯瑟琳·洛夫迪表示，婴幼儿虽然拥有短期记忆，但这些记忆并不持久。
This is possibly due to the rapid creation of brain cells in our early years.
这可能是因为我们在幼年时期，脑细胞处于快速增殖的阶段。
Some scientists also believe that as we get older, our childhood memories fade and after the age of seven, we get some kind of ‘childhood amnesia’.
一些科学家还认为，随着年龄增长，童年记忆会逐渐模糊，七岁之后，我们会出现某种程度的“童年健忘症”。
So why do we create fake memories?
那么，我们为什么会编造虚假记忆呢？
Some experts believe that there is a clear desire for a sense of self and having a cohesive story of our existence.
一些专家认为，这源于人们对自我认同感的明确渴望，以及想要构建连贯人生叙事的需求。
Creating memories can fill in the gaps – giving us a more complete structure for our early lives.
创造记忆能够填补人生的空白，让我们的成长阶段有更完整的脉络。
As we get older, we want to have a complete picture of our entire lives.
随着年龄增长，我们都希望拥有一段完整的人生图景。
So, the next time someone says they have a clear memory from when they were one – or even before - just remember that while it could be true, there’s a chance they just invented it at some point in their lives.
所以，下次再有人说自己清晰记得一岁甚至更小的时候发生的事，你要知道，这件事有可能是真的，但也有可能是他们在人生的某个阶段编造出来的。